### NIVETHA RAMACHANDRAN

Email: <u>niramach@syr.edu</u> Phone: 315-224-0700

LinkedIN URL: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nivetha-ramachandran

A skilled IT Engineer possessing technical and analytical knowledge backed with a good academic record and work experience. An enthusiastic professional having keenness and motivation to explore new fields of learning.

#### **EDUCATION:**

#### Master's in Computer Science, Syracuse University

May, 2020 (Expected)

Coursework: Software Modelling and Architecture, Computer Architecture, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Object Oriented

Programming in C++, Internet Programming

**GPA:** 3.33

### Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering, Mumbai University

July, 2013- May, 2017

Coursework: Data Structures, Analysis of Algorithms, Object Oriented Programming, Software Engineering, Data Warehouse and

Mining, Image Processing, Big Data Analysis

**GPA:** 3.5 (First Class with Distinction)

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS:

**Programming Languages:** C, C++, C#, Java, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

Software: MS Visual Studio, MS SQLServer, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

Operating System: Windows, Linux, Android

Database: SQL

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

# Software Developer | Ingram Micro SSC Pvt Ltd, India

July, 2017 - July, 2018

- Worked as a Software Developer in the Document To Order team in the Asia Pacific department at Ingram Micro.
- Conceptualized and developed portals using C# and ASP.NET having various functionalities as requested by the Business Team.
- Automation and monitoring of purchase order creation in SAP for various clients in the Asia Pacific region.
- Played a vital role in the Vendor Invoice Management project by coordinating with business teams to process Invoices and other related documents like Purchase Order/Credit Note/ Debit Note. This system helped the business and warehouse teams to keep track of goods received.
- Maintained project records on the demand management portal for the reference of Business and Finance departments.
- Established and obtained approvals for project timelines from the business team leads.

### Intern | Godrej Infotech Pvt Ltd, India

June, 2016 - July, 2016

- Worked as a Summer Intern in the Web Development Team.
- Developed an interactive and responsive online journal to summarize the company events for the INFOTECH department using HTML,CSS, Bootstrap, Java Script.

#### **ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE:**

### Lexical Analyzer, Syracuse University

**August**, 2018 – **December**, 2018

• Developed a lexical analyzer for the purpose of code analysis in .Net Framework using C#. The output of a State-Based Tokenizer was used by a Parser for dependency analysis and determination of strongly connected components. A Server-Client Model having the provision of an asynchronous message passing channel was also developed to showcase the implementation.

### **Ease Of Bus Transportation Using Big Data Analytics**

July, 2016 - March, 2017

- The irregularity in frequency and non-availability of adequate number of buses in high demand areas are targeted in the project.
- Considering the data collected in discrete time slots and making use of classification algorithms, buses are rerouted from areas of less demand to those with more demand.

#### JustHeli

January, 2016 - March, 2016

• Developed a demo website using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, which will help quicken the pace of the disaster relief activities. Users can report a disaster, as well as volunteer and sponsor for the same.

### **Quizzies**

**July, 2015 – December, 2015** 

• Development of a demo Android application with categorised questions to enable users to prepare for competitive examinations.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS:**

- Presented a paper on smart wallet in TechXter, a national level technical paper presentation held at SIES Graduate School of Technology
- Secured second place in Eyantra automatic car parking system competition (Robotics Competition) held at SIES Graduate School of Technology.